In this video, we will learn how to make a wave folding skirt.
First, we create a rectangle that is the same width and length as the waistband, and sew it to the waistband.
Here we freeze the waistband.
After sewing, we can open the model and let the board wear on the body.
When it is worn on the body, we can see that if it is a rectangular board, when it is sewed together with the waistline, there will be a missing piece in the front and back, similar to the triangle part.
So we have to fill in this triangle to make it look like a skirt.
If you want to fill it in, here we use the extension tool, click the extension line,
then
cut it open.
After opening the arrangement point, arrange this board on the arrangement point on the side.
Then pull the shoulder strap a little bit, so that this board and the model do not have penetrations.
When you start modeling, you can put the board on your body.
If we are now modeling the waistband,
because the waistband is now in the waist, it is a relatively sharp corner, so the waistband will be pulled down.
So we need to do this here.
We need to do a circular process on this corner.
After converting this point into a free curve point, we look at the model, its overall effect will be much better.
In addition, we can also convert the two straight points at the bottom into free curve points.
Usually we see some skirts like this, its front and back are relatively short and the back is relatively long.
So we just need to move this point in the process, press ctrl,
and we can move this point along this side of the curve.
After moving the point, we can see that this structure is now the structure of the front, long and back.
Now we can see that the overall effect is that the bottom is very obvious here, there are some waves, and then it is front, long and back.
If we need to make it longer or make its fold more obvious, we can continue to do this.
If the fold is more obvious, we can continue to use the extension tool to extend it to the front side and continue to unfold this board.
After unfolding, we need to delete the excess straight points and press c to open the editor tool.
After using the editor tool, drag this straight line to make it a curve.
After opening the simulation, we can manually drag the board.
Then, because the center point is still relatively deep, so we need to deal with it a little.
leftover lines with this color.
Taking the area 0 to 2 mm and making
more posted out brく값 then let's do this.
Select the straight line on both sides, and then right-click to select the inner line according to the curve.
Here, expand the number, we will set it according to the need, no need for a three-digit number.
Then we use the flip-folder tool to single-click the mouse on the left side of the first inner line,
and then move the mouse to create a reference line.
If you want this reference line to be flipped, you can single-click it in the middle, and double-click after completion.
In our software, many commands are done by double-clicking the mouse.
After the selection is complete, we select the winder here, because the winder will open at the end, and it will not overlap and meet.
So here, our inner line number 2 or 3 is the same, there will be no difference.
Then simulate it in the 3D window.
Here we can see that if we follow the previous method of making a blade,
directly print this version and simulate it, it will be folded together.
For example,
for our skirt, we don't need it to fold so close,
so here I will not use the print, but directly simulate it in the 3D space.
After simulation, we use the positioning ball tool to rotate it to the side of the virtual model.
There is no difference between virtual models and virtual models.
Then select the sewing line, right-click to activate the sewing line.
Then here, we will not use the seamstress button function,
but directly use the sewing line or free sewing to sew.
So like this, it will not interfere with the seamstress.
We call it a living seamstress.
That is, this seamstress, its mouth is open, it is not folded like before.
Then here, I have created more inner lines, so I will make it more obvious.
Of course, if we want the total amount of seamstresses to be less than this,
then when we first create the inner lines according to the curve,
we don't need to create as many as 30.
Next, we just press Ctrl D to create a symmetrical version.
Then we sew the front and back center together.
If we want to add a total length here, we can't pull this curve directly.
Because after pulling this curve, the straight lines on both sides of the left and right will be stretched.
So here, we need to select the panel line expansion.
After selecting the panel line expansion, we can set its expansion distance, which is the total length to be added.
Then the side angle, here we need to select extend.
In this way, the straight line on the side is along the original curve.
Then use the edit panel tool to double-click on a panel line,
and double-click again to select the panel line on the entire panel.
Then right-click to select align to the panel line, and that's it.
If you want to fold it quickly, you can do this.
You can temporarily print it and then unzip it.
Because the part of the panel line is extended, there is no panel line,
so here, use the edit panel line tool to adjust the length of the panel line,
and let them match.
Finally, we can reduce the particle strength first,
and then delete these internal lines,
and double-click to briefly simulate.
and then double-click to briefly simulate.
If you want to keep the current shape of the entire panel,
you can select these two panels and right-click to select shape optimization.
In this way, even if we manually drag the panel,
it can also maintain the previous simulation effect very well.
That's it for this video.
See you next time, bye bye.